[Music]
Welcome. My name is Buaj Kotayoko. In
this session, we will talk about
integration between business central and
field service. Both of those products
coming from Dynamics 365 family uh from
Microsoft. Of course, Dynamics 365 field
service is a leading product for
frontline workers, for technicians, for
companies who operate in the field and
has fantastic set of features uh related
to operating service management doing
service management in the field.
Business Central is connected to field
service through an integration that
gives you uh improved efficiency uh
reduced cost of operations and of course
ma makes sure that uh information
between field service and business
central uh is in sync. Uh that
integration is included uh out of the
box in business central and that of
course reduces implementation costs uh
for you and for your company. We also
have attractive pricing because with
Business Central premium license you
have a right to buy an attach license
for field service for just
$20. Integration between Business
Central and field service was already
announced and released last year. This
was the basic integration for projects.
In this wave, we are releasing
additional functionality that uh
includes uh integration with service
model in business central and that's why
uh a premium license for business
central is required. You might have seen
videos talking about both of those
integrations released last year
information circulating on social media.
Uh and um this is all now finally coming
to you in 25
uh wave 1. This integration is based on
data vers data sync technology. So you
need to enable that in your business
central instance and of course you need
dynamics 365 sales integration and then
field service integration both types
project and services in order to see
everything. Uh also you need virtual
tables enabled in your environment
meaning that you can see data from
business central directly in data
versse. This might sound overwhelming,
but there is actually a very easy wizard
in assisted setup that guides you
through the whole process. And at the
end, when you install a field service
and you want to enable it, you will see
uh a screen like this showing you two
types of integration, projects, and that
was the the standard feature released
last year, and services and projects,
which is what we are releasing right
now.
Along the way, you will be asked to
download the field service integration
app from AppSource. Uh, and of course,
that is needed. This is an extension
that is not installed directly in
Business Central. You have to install it
from AppSource to to have all of those
uh field service features built in. And
of course, the best way uh is to see it
in the demo.
This is my business central and it's
already set up with field service. I
don't want to show you how it is done
because it's it takes a little bit of
time but I just wanted to point you to
this assisted setup wizard for field
service. This is what needs to be done
in order to set it up. This company uh
is offering coffee machines and sold
some coffee machines through Trey uh
research. So this is the coffee machine
that was sold to this company and uh as
you can see Business Central already
created a service item. I have also
created a service order for this is the
last one
here for uh tray research and for this
particular coffee machine and I can see
in the service lines some coffee beans
replacement filter and some repair one
hour of work to provide some maintenance
so it's all on the business center side
and this service order is already
synchronized here with field service.
Clicking this button work order. I can
go to field service directly and see it
over there. So let's try
it. Here I'm in Dynamics 5 field service
and I can see this uh work order. Um I
can see that it has the replacement
parts that I needed and I also see the
services here and I can see that this
work order
uh is one of the unscheduled ones. So I
can go to schedule board here and in a
nice visual way I can see all of those
uh orders that are already assigned to
my uh employees to my service people and
then I can see also unscheduled work
orders here. So let's take this this one
for tray research and I would like to
assign it to Lena. So, I will drag and
drop it here and schedule
uh this repair and this visit with a
customer uh for Lena later
today. It's all good. And now I can go
back to my work orders. And I can see
that this uh work order is already
scheduled to be uh actioned by Lena. And
of course, she can rebook, she can uh
move it to someone else. And then uh
when done mark it as completed and it
will all already be indicated here in
field service. That's it for the quick
demo. We have plenty of information
about this integration published in our
documentation. So please have a
look. We also have published a field
service integration pitch deck. So this
is mostly for our partners where you can
also find more information and and uh
ready to to use material uh for your for
your operations. And then we also have
already videos as mentioned published
last year. So I was I would highly
recommend you to have a look and view
those videos as well on top of the the
one that you just uh just saw right now.
All right, this is it. Thank you very
much for watching.